

Bangalore, India

🛮 (+91) 87-8898-4877 | 🗷 patelshoeb4@gmail.com | 🏕 shoebpatel.com | 🖸 CaptainFreak | 🛅 iamshoebpatel | 💆 @0xCaptainFreak

"Exploits are the closest thing to 'magic spells' we experience in the real world: Construct the right incantation, gain remote control over device." - halvarflake

Summary.

Currently Security Engineer for the AppSec Team @Flipkart. 2+ years of experience specializing in Security Engineering, Threat Modeling, Application Security Reviews, DevSecOps, Security Automation, Penetration Testing and BugBounty Program Management. A Wannabe 10x Hacker and Engineer who closely follows the technology plain of Web Security, Back-end Engineering and Security Research.

Work Experience

FlipkartBangalore, India

SECURITY ENGINEER

- Owning a security charter for Engineering Teams and Business Units, integrating application security into every step of the SDLC by Delivering to all of the Application Security needs of each stage of the Software Life Cycle.
- Providing Architecture Reviews early in the Development stages of products.
- Recurring Threat-Models, Code Reviews, Complete Application Reviews of Web Apps, Micro-Services and Mobile Applications.
- Developing AppSec Services and Automation around the DevSecOps practices.
- Managing a private Invite-only BugBounty Program.
- Evangelising and creating a culture of security through recurring training and CTF competitions for Engineering Counterparts.

BrowserStack Mumbai, Inda

Security Engineer Jun. 2019 - Oct, 2019

- One of the initial members of the BootStrapped Security Engineering team.
- Built scalable in-house solution for real-time detection of Source Code, Credentials leakage on the public internet.
- Deployment of SIEM for anomalous AWS events, Network, and Application Layer events.
- · Red Teaming on production Apps.
- Threat Models and Security Reviews of Products.
- Application Inventory Management from Security Point of View.

Google Remote

STUDENT DEVELOPER, GSOC 18 & MENTOR, GSOC 19

Apr. 2018 - Jun. 2019

Oct. 2019 - Present

- As a mentor in Google Summer of Code 2k19, gave guidance to selected students for the project of OWASP foundation's Juice Shop Vulnerable Javascript application. The domain of the Project was Web Application Security, CTF challenges, and Web Development.
- In the year 2018, before being a mentor, I myself worked as a Student Developer under Mentor-ship of OWASP Juice-Shop's project maintainer.
- Built 12 challenges (Medium-Hard Difficulty) and Web functionalities around them.
- Project involved writing frontend in Angular, Backend in Node (expressJS) and Multiple test writing libraries separately for unit, integration and E2E tests.
- Databases in the design were MongoDB and SQLite.

UnderDawgs India

• UnderDawgs is a nascent CTF team, which participates in the world-wide CTFs around the year.

- Leading the team of hackers to excel at vulnerability research and capture the flag competitions. (CTFtime Id: 60327)
- Personally focused on Web Security Challanges and Research.

HackerOne & BugCrowd Remote

BUG BOUNTY HUNTER & FREELANCE HACKER

FOUNDER & CAPTAIN

Mar. 2018 - Jun. 2019

Dec. 2019 - Present

· Developed pragmatic knowledge and methodology to approach Black Box Hacking Targets.

- Participated in multiple Private and Public Bug Bounty Programs maintaining perfect Signal of 7.0 with 100% accuracy and gaining several Rewards.
- Hackerone Profile: https://hackerone.com/0xcaptainfreak
- BugCrowd Profile: https://bugcrowd.com/CaptainFreak

PERITUS INC.

Pune, India

SECURITY ENGINEERING INTERN

Mar. 2018 - May. 2018

- Developed complete Web Application in Spring and AngularJS that was used as a Training Lab for teaching prevalent vulnerabilities and best
 practices of Web Security.
- Contributed more than 20 API security challenges in the Labs.

DECEMBER 31, 2020 SHOEB PATEL · RÉSUMÉ

Miscellaneous work

HALL OF FAMES

- Google Amazon Web Services U.S. Department of Defense Oracle Dell Intel SalesForce MasterCard Western Union Marks and Spencer
- NetGear Codacy Visma MuleSoft DataDog UptyCS Smule TomTom Informatica

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

• Metasploit • OWASP Zaproxy • OWASP Juice Shop • Subfinder • Reconnoitre • NoSOLMap • GitDump • freeCodeCamp

Skills_

Security

• ThreatModeling • Web • APIs • Mobile • DevSecOps • Cloud • BugBounty • CTFs

Programming

• JavaScript • VueJS • NodeJs • Python • Algorithms • C • C++ • Java • Git

Tools & Frameworks

• BurpSuite • VueJS • Express • MongoDB

Program Committees

2020 **CTF Challenge Writer & Organizer**, BSides Ahmedabad 2020

Indic

Education

NIT Goa (National Institute of Technology)

Goa, India

B.Tech. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

July. 2015 - Apr. 2019

- Completed with CGPA of 8.53/10
- Major Courses: Network Security, Cryptography, Data Structure and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Database Systems, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Architecture and Compiler Design.

JNV Washim (Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya)

Maharashtra, India

B.Tech. In Computer Science and Engineering

Middle School - High School

- · Sports, Music, Computer Science and Hacking.
- High School Score: 93%
- SSC CGPA: 10/10

Extracurricular Activity

NITG Aficionados

FOUNDING PRESIDENT

Jan. 2017 - Apr. 2019

• Formed the geek society focusing on software engineering, competitive programming, problem solving and Career Development.

Community Link: https://github.com/NITG-Aficionados

DECEMBER 31, 2020 SHOEB PATEL · RÉSUMÉ 2